Harish Krishnan













SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with seven years of experience working in both big enterprises as well as startups. Have good experience in developing front-end, back-end, and mobile applications using several technologies. Also, have experience in being responsible for Application Security and DevSecOps topics. As an individual, a self-learner who strives to be a better software engineer than yesterday and always looking for opportunities to learn and implement new things. I also publish courses in Udemy and post videos in YouTube during my free time.

SKILLS

```
Programming Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, Go (Acquiring),
Rust(Acquiring).
Front-end - ReactJS, Angular, VueJS, NextJS, HTML & CSS, HTMX,
SolidJS(Acquiring), Qwik(Acquiring), Svelte(Acquiring).
Back-end - ExpressJs, NestJS.
Mobile App - React Native.
Databases - MongoDB, Postgres.
DevOps Tools - Jenkins, Cloud Foundry, Github Actions, Travis CI, Docker.
Application Security - Fortify, WhiteSource, Checkmarx, etc.
Testing - Cypress, Jest, Protractor, Vitest.
```

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

- ZigLearn PR Review
- <u>Awesome SolidJS</u>
- Qwik Docs Corrections
 - o PR-4862, PR-4861, PR-4866, PR-4885, PR-5286

EXPERIENCE

Udemy - Instructor

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

- Developing courses in Udemy during my freetime
- <u>Udemy Instructor profile</u>

SAP Labs, Bangalore — Software Engineer

NOV 2020 - PRESENT

- Developing <u>Intelligent Real Estate solutions</u> web applications using Angular, SAP UI5, CAP, and Spring Framework.
- Responsible for maintaining Application Security, fulfilling product and security standards, developing and maintaining CI/CD pipelines.
- Developing applications by following SSDL methodology and automating the process through DevSecOps methodology.
- Developing HR Solution for Public Sector Companies

Fragma Data Systems, Bangalore - Front-end Developer

JUL 2020 - NOV 2020

 Developed banking solution using ReactJs, used Redux for state management, Redux Sagas for asynchronous actions, unit testing using Jest.

Freelance Developer, Estonia / India - Full Stack Developer

MAY 2019 - MAR 2020

- Worked as a full-stack developer for a startup in Estonia <u>FoodDocs</u> a digital food safety Saas solution.
- Developing front-end web applications using Angular and VueJs.
- Developing back-end using Laravel.
- Unit testing using Jest and E2E tests using Cypress.
- Also, developed server side rendered apps using NuxtJS and mobile app using Flutter.

Boeing, Bangalore — Software Engineer

DEC 2018 - MAY 2019

- Worked as a front-end developer developing web applications for aircraft using Angular.
- Also developed REST APIs using Spring Framework.

Freelance Developer, India - Front-end Developer

MAY 2017 - DEC 2018

 Worked for an aspiring entrepreneur in the USA as a front-end developer using Angular and NgRX store in developing a Real Estate solution.

Squash Apps, Coimbatore, IN — Software Engineer

SEP 2016 - MAY 2017

- Started as an entry level software developer.
- Used AngularJs, Angular, ReactJs, NodeJs and Ionic framework to develop web and mobile applications.
- Using above technologies developed e-commerce solution called <u>Panitr</u> and AtmosFi

EDUCATION

PSG College of Technology — Bachelor of Engineering

JUL 2011 - MAY 2015, Coimbatore

- Pursued Automobile Engineering
- Part of college SAE chapter
- Team Lead for Formula SAE team.
- Passed with First class & Distinction and with CGPA 8.51.

AWARDS

- Outstanding Performer Awarded Move SAP grants (2021-2022) at SAP Labs.
- ullet Top rated freelancer in $\underline{\text{Upwork}}$

PERSONAL DETAILS

```
DOB - 24th September 1993

Human Languages - English, Tamil

Nationality - Indian
```

DECLARATION

Ι	do	hereby	declare	that	the	above	information	provided	is	true	to	my
C	once	ern.										

DATE:			
PLACE:			

SIGNATURE